什么？这是什么？
What? What is it?
酒烩肉卷。
你知道，填牛肉
It's braciole,
you know, stuffed beef.
真的？酒烩肉卷？
谁做的？
Really? Braciole?
Who made it?
我做的
I did.
试试总可以吧
Just try it.
-你没来点？
-不，一点……
- You're not having any?
- No, I had some...
你知道，给孩子们。
我让孩子们吃了点
you know, with the kids,
I had some with the kids.
哦。
你有什么感觉？
Oh.
How are you feeling?
没下毒，雷。
我要是想杀你，也不是这么杀法
It's not poisoned, Ray. If I wanted
to kill you, I wouldn't do it that way.
那好，我会记录在案的
All right,
that goes in the file.
嘿！
Hey!
-还行吧？
-是的！
- Good?
- Yeah!
是，好极了
Yeah, good.
第二口感觉更好
Even better
the second time
因为舌头没有恐惧了
now that my tongue's
not scared.
-嗯蓿乖乖，真是好极了
-是吗，你真的喜欢？
- Mmm, man, this is great.
- Yeah, you really like it?
很好。
我喜欢。让我接着吃
It's good.
I really do. Let me at it.
哦，那真是……
我开心死了！
Oh, that's...
I'm so happy!
哦，看，你坐下了！
Oh, look,
you're sitting down!
哦！
Ooh!
-我成功了！我真的做到了！
-妈咪！
- I did it, huh? I really did it!
- Mommy!
知道了，亲爱的，我这就上来
Yeah, honey, I'll be up
in just a second.
好了，我去浴室帮爱丽穿衣服
Okay, I'm gonna get
Ally out of the bath.
-灶台上还有的是
-留不久了
- There's a lot more on the stove here.
- Not for long.
嗯……
Mmm...
嘿，试试这个
Hey, try this.
-这是什么？
-酒烩肉卷
- What is it?
- Braciole.
-酒烩肉卷？
-我来
- Braciole?
- I'm in.
-谁做的？
-黛比拉
- Who made it?
- Debra.
我不来了
I'm out.
拿这来，雷，
我来试试黛比拉的酒烩肉卷
Here, Ray, I'll try
Debra's braciole.
反正我吃的抗生素够多
I'm filled
with antibiotics.
嗯蓿
Mmm!
是吗？
给我，给我
Yeah?
Gimme gimme.
-老天爷爷！
-明白了？
- Geez, oh Lou!
- See?
那么说的确不错。
不是因为我刚吃过飞机上的东西
So it is good. It's not just me
coming off airline food.
太奇妙了。
我是说，太妙了
It's amazing.
I mean, that is amazing.
你确定是你家的黛比拉做的？
Are you sure
your Debra made this?
我知道，我也不相信
I know, I couldn't
believe it either.
-她不知哪搞的菜谱
-菜谱？
- She came up with some recipe.
- Recipe?
-是的，怎么了？
-真正的厨师不需要菜谱
- Yeah, what?
- Real cooks don't need recipes.
我们知道怎么加进
爱和关怀
We know how to add
love and caring
因为任何快乐都比不上做吃的给……
because there's no greater joy
than feeding our...
弗兰克，瞧你的猪相
Frank,
you're a pig.
别吧唧了！
Stop moaning!
这么说黛比拉会做饭了
So Debra can
now cook.
雷蒙德彩虹上缺失的那一抹
The missing color
in the Raymond rainbow.
啊哈！
Ah ha ha ha ha!
你该问问黛比拉她是怎么做的
You should ask Debra
how she makes this.
我该问黛比拉？
I should ask Debra?
给我！
Gimme that!
这个食物有神奇的力量
This food has
magical powers.
我要在脖子上缠点
I'm gonna string some
of this around my neck.
-哈喽
-嘿，安迪
- Hello.
- Hey, Andy.
嘿，黛比，雷在吗？
Hey, Deb,
is Ray here?
不，他不在。
他还没回来
No, he's not home.
No, he's not home yet.
嘿，饿吗？
Hey, you hungry?
哦，当然，我最喜欢吃的了
Oh, sure, I could
always go for something.
我做了点酒烩肉卷。
来尝尝
I made some braciole.
Taste it.
噢，你做的……
呃……
Oh, you made...
Uh...
不不不，事实上……
No no no,
I'm actually...
我正在训练
I'm in training.
我正在训练赛跑
I'm in training
for a running thing.
-来吧
-不，真的
- Come on.
- No, no really.
并且，我只能吃
符合犹太教规的食物了
And I've gone kosher.
我参加了一个犹太人马拉松
I'm in a Jewish
marathon.
好吧……
Okay...
试一下，好吗？
一口，就一口
Try it, okay?
One bite, one bite.
好极了。就一口
That's it.
One.
和我跑路吧
Run away with me.
真的，你喜欢？
Really, you like it?
哦，我的天，不可思议！
Oh my God,
it's fantastic!
-嗯蓿黛比拉！
-怎么？
- Mmm, Debra!
- Yeah?
棒极了！
It's great!
我不知道雷说的什么意思
I don't know what
Ray's talking about.
什么意思，“说的”？
What do you mean,
"talking about"?
没什么，他只是上班时开开玩笑罢了
Nothing, he was just
trying to be funny at work.
玩笑？
这个？
Funny?
About this?
他拿我的酒烩肉卷开玩笑？
Was he making fun
of my braciole?
不，他没有
No, he was not.
等等，安迪。
他说他喜欢我的肉卷的
Wait, Andy. Andy, he told me
he loved my braciole.
What did he say
to you about it?
他对你怎么说的？
我有没有让你看过我怎么耸耳朵？
看这个……
Did I ever show you how
I can wiggle my ears? Look at this...
安迪，安迪。
他到底说的什么？
Andy, Andy.
What did he say about the braciole?
-我没觉出来可笑
-安迪！
- I did not find it funny.
- Andy!
他说那是意大利语
“过路车撞死的动物”
He said it was Italian
for "road kill. "
别伤害我
Please don't hurt me.
“过路车撞死的动物”？
"Road kill"?
他搞搞笑罢了，
就像他一直做的那样
He was just kidding around
like he always does.
他一直这样？
He always does this?
不，不……
No no...
听着，我刚吃了点感冒片
Listen, I had some
TheraFlu earlier.
然后我意识到我甚至没感冒
And then I realized
I do not even have the flu,
我感觉飞起来了，
晕乎晕乎的
so I'm really flying,
whoo-hoo-hoo!
-嘿。嘿
-哦，嘿
- Hey. Hey.
- Oh, hey.
嘿，你的资料，看到了？
Hey, hey, here's your stats,
all right?
以后你自己去取。
我受够了
From now on, you get them
on your own. I'm tired of this.
你和安迪上床了？
你可以找个更好的
Are you sleeping with Andy?
'Cause you can do better.
-有意思
-是的
- That's funny.
- Yeah.
哦，什么这么香？
Hey, what
smells good?
哦，我又做酒烩肉卷了。
你知道，因为你这么喜欢
Oh, I made braciole again.
You know, 'cause you liked it so much.
是的，我喜欢！
Yes, I do!
七彩的虹呀！
All the colors
in the rainbow!
哦，真叫个香
Oh, that smells good.
#黛比拉做了好东东#
# Debra made
something good! #
#哇哇哇哇#
# Mwah mwah
mwah mwah mwah #
#雷蒙德好好喜欢#
# Raymond really
likes it #
#SS#
# Yeah-hah #
#你就该做做#
# You ain't got to
make nothing else #
#酒烩肉卷#
# But that braciole #
#呼哈呼哈呼#
# Hoo-hah hoo-hah hoo! #
#我可以吃这个#
# I could eat this stuff #
#直到失去控制#
# Until I lose contro-ol #
#瓦卡哈瓦卡哇哈哈#
# Wack-ha wacka-wa
ha-hah... #
#瓦卡哈……#
# Wacka-hah... #
“给你点汁，撞死的动物”
Here's a little sauce
for your road kill.
#咻……#
# Hoo... #
#呜……#
# Woo... #
#怎么了？#
# What? #
你不想听就直接说
“别唱了”
You could have just said,
"Please don't sing. "
食物很好。
不过我对服务有几句话说
Food here is good. I might have
a comment about the service.
你在上班的时候就这么取笑我的？
你一整天都拿我开心？
Is that what you do at work?
You make fun of me all day?
什么？
不，安迪说的？
What?
No, is that what Andy said?
哦，他干吗这么说？
Oh, why the hell
would he say that?
我不知道，
但他是真的喜欢我的肉卷
I don't know but he actually
loved my braciole.
我爱你的肉卷！
I love your braciole!
别这样，这是你做得最好的了！
Come on, it's the best thing
you ever made!
哦，别废话了！
那你为什么说那是撞死的动物？
Oh baloney! How come you told
everybody it was road kill?
-那是个玩笑
-哦，不，不是的
- That's a joke.
- Oh no, it's not.
当然是的！
我只是开个玩笑罢了
Of course it is!
I was just kidding.
行了，你知道我有多喜欢的
Come on, you see
how much I love it.
我得用用毛巾
I could use
a towel.
哈喽，黛比拉
Hello, Debra.
-怎么回事，弗兰克？
-没事，亲爱的
- What is it, Frank?
- Nothing, dear.
我只是想你这还有没有
美味的酒烩肉卷剩下。
I was just wondering if there was any
of your delicious braciole left.
哦，这是给你的
Oh, these are for you.
哦，爸，别这会，
求你了，好吗？
Oh, Dad, not now,
please, all right?
嘿，你裤子上有点污点
Hey, you got
a little spot there.
我告诉你，黛比拉，
你做的东西太棒了
I'm telling you, Debra,
that stuff you made is so great,
我一大早起来就像着它
I woke up
thinking about it.
这个有人吃吗？
Is anybody
eating this?
没有，弗兰克。
你知道，你可以吃这个
No, Frank. You know what?
You can have it.
至少还有人喜欢
At least someone
appreciates it.
-嘿，我喜欢
-谢谢你的话，弗兰克
- Hey, I appreciate it...
- Thank you for the flowers, Frank.
能做这样的肉卷的人
应该得到一整片
Anyone who can make braciole
like this deserves a whole hillside
开满金盏和水仙的山坡
full of heavenly-scented marigolds
and daffodils.
我正好同意他的观点……
I happen to agree
with him...
真动人，弗兰克
That's very sweet,
Frank.
这是很久以来我听到的最动听的话了
That's the nicest thing anybody's
said to me in quite some time.
想来点喝的吗？
Would you like
something to drink?
不，我不想冲淡了原有的风味
No, I don't want
to dilute the flavor.
请坐下
Please sit down.
你该把脚抬起来休息休息
You should be resting
with your feet up.
谢谢，弗兰克
Thank you, Frank.
-好了，得了
-怎么了，雷？
- All right, come on.
- What's the matter, Ray?
我没被嘲笑而是受人称赞
有什么不对劲吗？
Is it so weird that I'm being
appreciated instead of mocked?
-我就是这么带大你的？
-好吧，爸
- Is that how I raised you?
- Yeah, okay, Dad.
嗯蓿太好吃了
Mmm, this is
so delicious.
你真的到家了，孩子
You really
got it, kid.
你真的这么想？
Do you really think so?
有种特别的甜味。
你怎么做的？
There's just like a sweetness to it.
How do you do that?
你知道，有些人用葡萄干，
我用的黑醋栗
Well you know, some people
use raisins, but I had some currants.
-真是美好的东西
-谢谢，弗兰克
- This is a beautiful thing.
- Thank you, Frank.
我以为你在洗澡
I thought you were
taking a bath.
我是洗了。
洗完了
I was.
I finished.
哦
Oh.
洗的好吗？
How was it?
很好，弗兰克。
谢谢你给我准备洗澡水
It was fine, Frank.
Thank you for making it for me.
你有35年没给我准备洗澡水了
You haven't made a bath
for me in 35 years.
呃，你看起来需要
Uh, you seemed
to need it.
听着，玛丽，
并不是你想的那样
Listen, Marie,
this is not what it looks like.
我不是来找你说话的
I'm not talking
to you.
不过， 我有话要问黛比拉
I do have a question
for Debra, however:
我做了什么，
你非要毁了我？
What have I done that you
feel the need to destroy me?
什么？
What?
谁跟你说的酒烩肉卷的？
Who told you
about braciole?
没人，我从杂志上找到的
Nobody.
I found a recipe in a magazine.
你找着菜谱了？
哦，你现在成厨师了！
You found a recipe?
Oh, you're a cook now!
-弗兰克从没更你说过酒烩肉卷？
-没有
- Frank never mentioned braciole to you?
- No.
-不
-不，我什么都没说，玛丽……
- No.
- No, I didn't say a thing, Marie...
安静
Quiet.
弗兰克从没告诉你
Frank never told you
that braciole
酒烩肉卷是我给做的第一道菜？
was the very first thing
I ever cooked for him?
哦，乖乖
Oh, boy.
-不，我不知道
-你不知道？
- No, I didn't know that.
- You didn't know that?
你知道1959年
Do you know
what he said to me
他吃过我做的酒烩肉卷后
说了什么？
when he tasted
my braciole in 1955?
他说：
“做我的新娘吧”
He said,
"Be my bride. "
-玛丽，行了
-“做我的新娘吧”，弗兰克
- Marie, come on.
- "Be my bride," Frank.
“做我的新娘吧”
"Be my bride. "
不过显然只要是
有锅的姑娘都能做你新娘
But it's very clear now
that you'll go to any girl with a pot.
你几乎再没给我做过！
You hardly make it
for me anymore!
因为我不想让你吃腻了
'Cause I didn't want
you to get sick of it.
我都64岁了
I'm 64 years old.
你还留着等什么？
What are you
saving it for?
玛丽，我很抱歉。
我不知道那是你的特别菜
Marie, I'm sorry.
I didn't know it was your special dish.
你就没有别的家务
Don't you have other
household things
需要照顾的，比如……
that you need
to take care of like...
比如洗衣服？
like the laundry?
雷蒙德，把裤子给我
Raymond, give me those pants.
-我来洗
-没事的，妈
- I'll wash them.
- It's okay, Mom.
不，我来给你洗裤子，
该死的！
No, I'm washing those
pants for you, damn it!
-妈……
-把裤子脱了！
- Mom...
- Take off your pants!
能把暖气开大点吗？
Could we turn
the heat up?
你想让我说什么？
What do you want me
to say, Marie?
“对不起我做酒烩肉卷了”？
"I'm sorry
I made braciole"?
真是疯了！
要是知道会弄得这么天翻地覆
This is insane!
I never would have made the stuff
我才不会做这鬼东西
if I thought it was gonna
turn everybody's world upside-down.
嘿，妈，我没吃的了
Hey, Ma, I have nothing
to eat over there.
你说给我做晚饭的
You said you were
making me dinner.
我不做饭了
I don't cook anymore.
罗伯特，雷蒙德
嘲笑过多少我做的饭？
Robert, how much does Ray
make fun of my cooking?
别看他
Don't look at him.
不许看他，罗伯特！
Don't you look
at him, Robert!
-他没穿裤子……
-回答我！
- He's not wearing pants...
- Answer me!
我知道他拿我做的饭开心
I know he makes fun
of my cooking.
我只想知道他在我背后
说了多少次
I want to know how much of it goes on
behind my back.
他一向这样，亲爱的
He makes fun of it
all the time, dear.
这不是真的！
That is not true!
这不是完全真实的，黛比拉！
That's not
completely true, Debra!
我爱你的肉卷，
而且我今天不是说谎
I love your braciole
and I am not lying today.
所以你就寻开心，
上班时开玩笑？
Is that why you're making fun of it,
making jokes about it at work?
你拿这道菜开玩笑？
You make jokes
about this food?
-你不知道什么叫得体吗？
-哦，得了吧，爸！
- Have you no decency?
- Oh stop. Come on, Dad!
那只是……
你知道，那只是……
It's just...
You know, it's just...
老婆玩笑，就这样
wife jokes,
that's all.
和男人们在一起时做的事
It's something you do when, you know,
when you're with the guys.
-我就从没有
-哦，你说什么呢？
- I never.
- Oh, what are you talking about?
好像你就没讲笑话似的
Like you don't
make jokes.
首先，
我如果有关于你妈的话要说
First of all, if I have anything
to say about your mother,
我不怕当她面说
I'm not afraid to say it
right to her face.
其次，那些也不是笑话
Second of all,
those are not jokes.
昨天你叫我丑八怪
Yesterday you called me
an old bag.
如果那是笑话，
也是笑我自己
If that's a joke,
then it's on me.
就当着她的面！
Right in front of her!
事实上，不是袒护雷蒙德，
那不过是男人们惯常的事，黛比拉
Actually, not to defend Raymond,
that is a guy thing, Debra.
我常常发现男人们开老婆的玩笑
I've often found that men
use the wife joke to, uh,
以联系感情，分享共同经历
form bonds and share
common experiences.
我是不是坐在酱上了？
Am I sitting
in sauce?
是的，罗伯特
Yes,
Robert.
那就好。
我还担心是我把裤子崩掉了
Good.
I was afraid I popped a stitch.
罗伯特，来，把裤子脱了
Robert, come on.
Take off those pants.
-什么？
-脱掉！
- What?
- Take them off!
-你说的什……
-裤子归我！
- Well, what do you...
- I get those pants!
别争了，兄弟，别争
Don't fight it, man,
don't fight it.
快点，我们回家。
我给你收拾收拾
Come on, let's go home,
I'll clean you up.
好的
All right.
谢谢，妈
Thanks, Ma.
-你走是不走？
-当然走了
- Are you coming or not?
- Of course I'm coming.
你是我老婆，我属于你
You're my wife.
I belong with you.
我来了
I'm coming.
我给你打电话
I'll call you.
我去洗巴洗巴
I'm gonna go
freshen up.
雷，我能跟你谈谈吗？
Ray, can I talk
to you?
当然，好的。
不过……
Yeah, all right,
but...
我有点点冻
I'm a little
chilly.
你为什么非得开老婆玩笑？
Why do you have to
make wife jokes?
我不那么做，
我不开老公玩笑
I don't do that.
I don't make husband jokes.
你不会告诉我
你没跟艾米、琳达出去
Are you telling me that you don't go
out with Amy and Linda
取笑我做的那些傻事，你知道的？
and make fun of all
the stupid things I do, you know?
你没说我念书时嘴巴怎么动
You don't talk about
the way my lips move when I read
或者有一次你逮到我要脚趾甲
or you caught me biting
my toenail that one time
或者，或者……
or or or that...
不，我没有。
事实上，我努力朝另一边说
No, I don't. In fact, I try to spin it
in the other direction.
琳达以为你有马斯特的？
Linda thinks you
have a master's.
马斯特的？
Master's?
学位。
硕士学位，雷
Degree.
Master's degree, Ray.
这就是我弄不明白的了
This is what I don't
understand.
你总是嘲笑我做的饭
You're always making fun
of my cooking,
而我终于做了你喜欢的东西
but I finally
make something you like
而你还是拿来开玩笑。
为什么？
and you're still making
jokes about it. Why?
我是个复杂的人
I'm a complicated
person.
别这样，那只是……
我就是那样子
Oh, come on, it's just...
that's who I am.
我拿妻子开开玩笑
I make fun of
the wife a little.
“哦，雷来了……
雷，她昨晚对你干了什么？”
"Oh here's Ray...
Ray, what did she do to you last night?"
如果我说：
“她做了酒烩肉卷，味道好极了”
And if I say, "She made some braciole
and it was quite tasty,"
哇……
谁想跟这种人一块玩？
wha... who wants
to hang out with that guy?
不过你不认为有什么不对劲吗？
But don't you think that
there's something wrong
除了那我开玩笑没别的办法
让别人喜欢？
that the only way you
can be popular is at my expense?
我希望能有别的办法
I wish there was
another way.
好吧……
All right...
噢，别这样
Aw, come on.
我开玩笑的
I'm kidding.
看， 咱们都知道咱俩几斤几两
Hey look, we know
the score here.
你哪样都比我强，不是吗？
You got it
all over me, right?
你是那个漂亮聪明集于一身的
好的那个
You're the pretty, smart,
together, good one.
而对我，他们说：
“他怎么娶到她的？”
I'm the one they say,
"How did he get her?"
所以，我不知道，
也许以我的傻方式
So I don't know,
maybe in my stupid way,
我告诉他们怎么回事
I'm telling them how.
你知道，
“她不会做饭。哈哈”
You know,
"She can't cook. Ha ha. "
啊哈哈
Ah ha ha ha ha.
怎么了？
What?
这还不是最糟的。
你认识查克・威尔森吧？
你知道他怎么对我说的？
It could be worse. You know Chuck
Wilson? You know what he told me?
他说她是那么冷感，
他和她一块上床的时候
He said his wife is so cold,
when he gets into bed with her,
必须要使劲把企鹅赶跑
he has to shoo away
the penguins.
赶跑企鹅
Shoo away
the penguins.
冷感。
威尔森的老婆
That's cold.
Wilson's wife.
然而……
And yet...
我对她的印象一点也没变坏
I don't think
any less of her.
我不在乎别的男人怎么想我
I don't care what the other guys
think about me.
我在乎的是你怎么想的
I care what you
think about me.
我再也不开玩笑了
I'm not gonna make
jokes anymore.
谢谢
Thank you.
你还会给我做饭吗？
Are you still
gonna cook for me?
是的
Yes.
想把裤子脱了吗？
Wanna take
your pants off?
不
No.
好吧，那我能再来点酱吗？
Okay, then can I
have more sauce?
哦，行了
Aw, come on.
行了……
Come on...
嘿，你在干什么？
Hey. What are
you doing?
我在喝茶
I'm having some tea.
-没做晚饭？
-做了，茶
- Didn't make any dinner?
- Yes, tea.
哦
Oh.
黛比拉今晚做什么了？
And what did Debra
make tonight?
宽面条
Lasagna.
完了
It's over.
怎么了？
What?
我想她就会做酒烩肉卷
I think that braciole
is all she can make.
听着，玛丽，
我明白了件事
Listen, Marie,
I learned something.
男人需要的不只是酒烩肉卷
A man needs more
than braciole.
男人需要……
A man needs...
鸡肉
chicken,
小牛肉，干酪酿茄子
veal, eggplant parmesan.
裹肉通心粉？
Manicotti?
是的，果肉通心粉
Yes, manicotti.
哦，弗兰克！
Oh, Frank!
-弗兰克
-什么？
- And Frank?
- Yes?
再也不许提这件事了
We'll never speak
of this again.
jojoba
yettoreturn@hotmail.com